Toni Morrison Papers, 1917-2015: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 5: Academic Career, 1984-2011; 12 boxes
  - Subseries 5B: Princeton University, 1986-2011; 3 boxes
    - Romance Languages and Literature, 1989-1999; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Saunders, Ronnie, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Sociology, 1993-1998; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Tanner Committee, 1996-2001; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Target of Opportunity Search Committee, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Toni Morrison Birthday-2/26/95, 1995; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Toni Morrison Birthday Party-2/26/94, 1994; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Toni Morrison Party-10/17/93, 1993; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Vice-President for Public Affairs, 1991-1993; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Wallace Fellowship, 1989; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Women's Studies, 1989-1995; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Women's Center/Third World Center/Center for Jewish Life/International Center, 1989-2002; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Woodrow Wilson School/Terrace Club, 1989-2000; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 5C: Teaching Files, 1985-2009; 7 boxes (1 partial)
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by course name, with separated restricted material (grades, evaluations, and student papers) listed at the end of the subseries.
    Course material includes notes, lectures, syllabi, annotated readings, and course packets. Atelier files include material relating to the administration of the interdisciplinary program and correspondence with instructors. Studies in American Africanism files include an unpublished manuscript drawn from the lectures given as part of this course.
    - The American Self/Selves, 1989; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Art and Culture in Modern Afro-American Fiction, 1989-1991; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Atelier, 1992-2009; portions of 2 boxes
      - American Ballet Theatre, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - Anonymous 4, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - Binnerts, Paul and Christine Jones, 2002-2004; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - Bodies in Evidence, 2006-2009; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 6)
      - Budgets, 1995-2004; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 7)
      - Danielpour, Richard, Yo Yo Ma, Edgar Meyer, and Toni Morrison, 1996; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 8)
      - Danielpour, Richard and Toni Morrison, 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 108, Folder 9-10)
      - Eckert, Rinde and Steve Mackey, 2003-2004; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 11)
      - Fundraiser: Carpenter/Waletzky Dinner, 2000; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 12)
      - Fundraiser: Frelinghuysen Cocktail Party, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 13)
      - Fundraising, 1997-2004; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 14)
      - Fundraising and Publicity Texts, 1996-2002; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 15)
      - Hagen, Daron and Paul Muldoon, 1998-2005; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 16)
      - Invitation Lists, 1997-2000; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 17)
      - Kahn, Nicholas and Richard Selesnick, 2002; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 18)
      - Kommunyakaa, Yusef, 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 19)
      - Lieberman, Erez, 2002; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 20)
      - Magnus, Erica, 2004-2005; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 21)
      - Manter, Nancy and Ben Shedd, 2001-2004; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 22)
      - Marquez, Gabriel Garcia, 1996-1998; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 23)
      - Miscellaneous, 1994-2005; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 24)
      - Modica, Andrea, 1999; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 25)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol and Susana Tubert, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 26)
      - Obadike, Mendi and Keith, 2003-2005; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 27)
      - Olson, Sarah, 2005; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 28)
      - Personal Correspondence, 1997-2005; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 1)
      - Pig Iron Theater, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 2)
      - Price, Richard, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 3)
      - Proposals, 1992-2008; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - Provost/Humanities Council, 1998-2005; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 5)
      - Publicity, 1997; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 6)
      - Reagon, Bernice Johnson, 1997; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 7)
      - Sadovska, Mariana, Roger Babb, Lars Jan, 2004-2005; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 8)
      - Sanderson, Christopher, 2001; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - Sellars, Peter, undated; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 10)
      - Tucci, Maria, Allegra Kent, Daniel Mendelsohn, 2004-2006; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Contemporary Black Women and Their Fiction, 1985; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Creative Writing, 1985-1994; 2 folders
      - Annotated Readings, undated; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 13)
      - Exercises, 1990-1994; portion of 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 14)
      - Syllabi, Schedules, Etc., 1985-1994; portion of 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - The Foreigner's Home: Studies in the Literature of Dispossession, 2007-2009; 2 folders (Box 109, Folder 16-17)
    - Global Fiction, 1998; 2 folders (Box 109, Folder 18-19)
    - On Morrison: The Literary Imagination, 1997; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 20)
    - Studies in American Africanism, 1987-1996; 3 boxes (2 partial)
      - Annotated Bibliography, undated; 2 folders (Box 109, Folder 21-22)
      - Annotated Readings, undated; 2 folders (Box 109, Folder 23-24)
      - Aunt Jemima Advertising and Identity, undated; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 1)
      - Book Orders/Library Reserve, 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 110, Folder 2-3)
      - Class Lists, 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 4)
      - Course Reader, 1992; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 5)
      - Course Reader, 1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Lecture: "The Matter of Africanism", circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 7)
      - Lecture: "Shadow and Flight", circa 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 110, Folder 8-9)
      - Lecture: "Surrogate Self as Enabler", circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 10)
      - Lecture: William Styron, circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 11)
      - Lecture: "Text and Context: Uncle Tom's Cabin", circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 12)
      - Lecture: Mark Twain, circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 13)
      - Lecture: Gertrude Stein, circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 14)
      - Lecture: William Faulker, circa 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 110, Folder 15-16)
      - Lecture: "Bellow: Henderson the Rain King", circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 17)
      - Lecture: "O'Connor and McCullers: Surrogate Enablers", circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 18)
      - Lecture: "Willa Cather: The Fugitive(s) Plot", circa 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 19)
      - Lectures, circa 1991-1993; 2 folders (Box 111, Folder 1-2, Box 110, Folder 20)
      - Manuscript, 1993; 2 folders (Box 111, Folder 3-4)
        With correspondence from Peter Dimock.
      - Miscellaneous Lecture Material, circa 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 110, Folder 5-6)
        See also Playing in the Dark
      - McBride, Dwight, 1989; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - McGowan, Tara, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 8)
      - Memos, 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 9)
      - Precepts/Preceptors, 1991-1996; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 10)
      - Racial Matters in Media, 1990; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 11)
      - Slides, 1989; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 12)
      - Study Questions and Paper Topics, 1989-1996; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 13)
      - Syllabi and Bibliographies, 1989-1996; 3 folders (Box 111, Folder 14-16)
      - Third World View of Western Canon, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 17)
      - Various Working Materials, circa 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 111, Folder 18-19)
    - Unidentified Class and Lecture Notes, undated; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Student Progress Notes, 1990 Spring; 1 folder (Box 112, Folder 1)
      This material is closed until 2084.
    - Class Record Books, 1989-1998; 5 folders (Box 112, Folder 2-6)
    - Atelier Student Critiques, 2005-2009; 2 folders (Box 112, Folder 7-8)
    - Course Evaluations, 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 112, Folder 9-10)
    - Grades and Critiques, 1989-2009; 3 folders (Box 112, Folder 11-13)
    - Student Papers, 1989-2009; 3 boxes (2 partial)
      Arranged alphabetically by the student's last name.
      - A-B, 1989-2009; 3 folders (Box 112, Folder 14-16)
      - Br-L, 1989-2009; 12 folders (Box 113, Folder 1-12)
      - M-Z, 1989-2009; 15 folders (Box 114, Folder 1-15)